manticoretechnology.com 2010-11-26

# Privacy Policy, Privacy Officer Contact, Data Collection Practices - Manticore Technology

The following information is intended specifically for Manticore Technology clients who visit the Manticore Technology web site and other visitors to the Manticore Technology web site. This policy covers how Manticore Technology treats personal information that we collect and receive from our site only. If you are looking for information regarding the software that we produce, how this software enables our clients to collect personal information and the privacy issues relating to the information that our clients gather, please see **"For visitors to the website of clients of Manticore Technology"** below.

For the Manticore Technology corporate site and for our online software services, we leverage our own products, Virtual Traffic Master, Virtual Commerce Master and Web Analytic Tool, to better use and analyze traffic on our web site. 

### What Information We Gather and How We Use It

For visitors to the Manticore Technology website who are not existing clients of Manticore Technology, we collect non-personally identifying information such as IP address, time of visit, click-sequence, and technical information about your browser. Non-personally identifying Information that we collect about the browsing habits of our visitors is used to optimize the design of our website by understanding what content our clients are interested in. We can then streamline the website to make it more user friendly for our visitors.

For current Manticore Technology clients, we collect personally identifying information as part of the Terms of Service for using any Manticore Technology product. This information includes such things as name, physical address, phone number, email address and other information for billing purposes. Current clients can correct or update this information by logging into their Manticore Technology account and using the appropriate section of the account management area. This information is used primarily for billing and contact purposes as it relates to the use of our products. 

Manticore Technology will NEVER sell any information that we have collected, personally identifying or otherwise, to a third party. This information is deemed proprietary information of Manticore Technology and will only be used by our staff.

### Communications from Manticore Technology

Manticore Technology may also send current clients email newsletters and announcements about new product releases or events. Additionally, we have the ability to monitor the sessions of current Manticore clients by username so that we can gauge usage levels and reenact client click streams for trouble shooting purposes. Manticore Technology respects the privacy of visitors to its web site and provides an option to all visitors to opt out or unsubscribe from all communications from Manticore Technology (see below). 

For non-Manticore Technology clients and Manticore Technology clients alike, we regularly track the results of our email campaigns by monitoring email metrics such as open, click-thru, and no response rates. We also collect email addresses and contact information via our website. If you have volunteered your email address to us or we have acquired it via a third party, we may be able to identify your session on our website by your email address. We use the results of our email monitoring to qualify prospective clients by identifying who is interested in what. Visitors who read our email more frequently or visit our site often and view information about our products are much more likely to be contacted than those who do not.

### Transfer of Data

It is always possible that Manticore Technology could participate in an acquisition or merger, either as an acquirer or an acquired entity. If another entity acquires Manticore Technology through a purchase or corporate transaction, all information previously collected by Manticore Technology, including non-personally identifiable information as well as personally identifiable information, would be transferred to the acquiring entity. In such event, Manticore Technology will safeguard the confidentiality of any personally identifiable information transferred to the acquiring entity. Manticore Technology will either (i) ensure that the privacy policies of the acquiring entity are at least as protective of the personally identifiable information as Manticore Technology's privacy policy, or (ii) provide you notice before any personally identifiable information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

### Access to Your Data

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you wish that your personally identifiable information no longer be used by Manticore Technology you may correct, update or delete your personally identifiable information by sending an email to Privacy@ManticoreTechnology.com. We will use good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personally identifiable information, correct the data if it is incorrect or incomplete or delete the data at your request (if it is not required by law to be retained). We may decline to respond to requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require excessive technical effort or resources, jeopardize the privacy rights of third parties or would be unreasonably 

### Opt Out / Unsubscribe

If you have received email communications from us and would like to opt-out of future mailings, please visit our unsubscribe page. Your email address will be permanently removed from our email lists.

You also have the ability, when asked for personally identifiable information, to elect not to have your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes. For example, if you purchase services from Manticore Technology but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from Manticore Technology, you may indicate your preference at that time.

## For visitors to the website of clients of Manticore Technology:

### Manticore Technology's Services to its Clients 

Manticore Technology is in the business of providing lead generation and marketing services to its clients, which services involve collecting information about visitors to a client's website. The data that Manticore Technology collects and analyzes for its clients helps the clients to understand how consumers are interacting with their website. Our software allows a client to identify ways to create a better visitor experience and ultimately reduce the cost of doing business. The more information our clients have, the more successful they will be at realizing that cost savings.

### Data Ownership

Our clients own the information collected using Manticore Technology's services. We store this information for them for the duration of our contractual agreement. Unless required by law, we will not divulge any statistics or other data collected by our products to any party other than our client. When a contract with one of our clients is terminated, we will keep data for a discretionary period of time after the termination of the contract, and then we will permanently delete or destroy such information. Our clients may retain that information for any length of time, in accordance with their respective privacy policies. 

The Manticore Technology privacy policy is complimentary to the privacy policy adopted by our clients and appearing on our clients' respective websites. Although Manticore Technology expects that its clients will comply with all laws and applicable regulations when using the Manticore Technology services, Manticore Technology does not make any warranty or guarantee as to how its clients may handle information obtained from or stored through our service. If we discover that a client of ours has engaged in unethical or illegal activities, Manticore Technology may suspend that client's services (after a warning) and may report such client to the proper authorities. If you have a concern about the policy of a particular client of Manticore Technology, please refer to that entity's website for their individual privacy policy or contact them directly. 

### What Information We Gather for Clients

When used by our clients, our software services collect non-personally identifying information such as IP address, domain name, pages that were viewed, the referral source of the, and technical information such as browser type and operating system. Additionally, our Commerce Master product captures transaction information, such as consumer shopping cart interaction, and check-out statistics such as purchase size and most popular products.

Depending on the level of service that a client selects, our software may also collect and use certain personally identifying information. Although we store this information for our clients, it is still owned by our clients. Furthermore, our software is not technically capable of gathering personal identifiable information from any consumer on our clients' behalf without consumer consent. Accordingly, any personally identifiable information that is stored in our system must have been collected with the consent of the consumer.

The personally identifiable information that our software uses includes email address, a site username, a physical address, a telephone number, and other information that a consumer has provided to our client (by signing up for services, by subscribing to emails, etc.). Personally identifiable information is NOT shared among our clients and is owned in whole by the client with the relationship with the consumer. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of our clients to learn how they may use this data.

Manticore Technology does not collect individual profile information across multiple client websites for aggregation. Our clients only have access to the data collected from their own respective websites, and we do not build an aggregate profile of a visitor's browsing habits.

### Consumer Opt-Out / Unsubscribe

Manticore Technology and our clients respect the privacy of individual consumers and their wish not to participate in any data gathering practices. There is a consumer opt-out feature on our clients' websites, although Manticore Technology does not control those features. We direct to you review the unsubscribe and/or opt out features on our clients' website if you want to unsubscribe to any email communications from that client or opt out of any data gathering activities.

## General Information Regarding Privacy Applicable to All Visitors:

### Data Security

The integrity and security of the data that we collect and store is our number one priority. Manticore Technology uses industry security best practices to insure that the data remains secure, including SSL encryption for data collection, proactive server security audits, proprietary encryption algorithms for database storage, redundant systems, and data backup.

Clients who use our service transmit raw data about their websites to our servers. Data that contains potentially sensitive information, including personally identifiable information, is sent using various encryption technologies. Manticore Technology processes and analyzes the data and then provides the results of that analysis to our clients, online, via secure reports.

### Use of Cookies and Web Beacons

When you visit Manticore Technology's web site or the website of a client of Manticore Technology, a cookie, or a small file of characters, is sent to your computer or other device that identifies your browser. All web browsers offer the option to refuse any cookie. If a consumer refuses the Manticore Technology cookie, Manticore Technology cannot collect any information on that consumer and such features as "Remember Me" will not work (requiring a consumer to re-enter information at each visit).

Manticore Technology also employs web beacons, which are anonymous objects embedded in a web site that enables the owner of the site to track who has read the site or what portion of the site was read. Manticore Technology uses web beacons in conjunction with cookies in order to improve the quality of our web site and the web sites of our clients. 

Neither cookies nor web beacons contain any personal identifiable information, but they do facilitate the general functionality of Manticore Technology’s online reporting tool. 

### Questions, Complaints and Enforcement

Manticore Technology participates in the Safe Harbor program developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Union. Manticore Technology has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles agreed upon by the U.S. and the E.U. You may visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor web site for more information about the Safe Harbor. 

If you have a question or complaint regarding Manticore Technology’s privacy policy or Manticore Technology's use of personal information, you may contact Manticore Technology through this web site or by writing us at the following address: 

Privacy Officer  
Manticore Technology Corporation  
9111 Jollyville Road, Suite 225  
Austin, TX 78759  
Email address: [privacy@manticoretechnology.com](mailto:privacy@manticoretechnology.com)

Manticore Technology will contact you regarding your concerns. If the complain or issue cannot be resolved directly by Manticore Technology, Manticore Technology will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including any local data protection authorities, to resolve an issue regarding the use of personal information.
